A Guide to the Howard Jacklin Rhodes Papers, 1955-1978
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Howard Jacklin Rhodes Papers, 1955-1978
The Library of Virginia
39380
9 cubic feet (20 boxes).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Lois Rhodes, Sitka, Alaska.
Biographical Information
Howard Jacklin "Jack" Rhodes was born in Springfield, Missouri on 9 July 1910. He was the son of William Ira Rhodes (1885-1974) and Pauline Elizabeth Jacklin (1891-1919). Rhodes attended Denver Junior College and Reed College. He was a manufacturer, distributor, and importer of hardwood lumber and lumber products. He married Eula Inez Murphy (b. 1917) in Homestead, Florida on 16 March 1934. Howard Jacklin Rhodes died on 27 January 1981 in Chula Vista, California.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1955-1978, of Howard Jacklin Rhodes (1910-1981) of San Bernardino and Siskiyou Counties, California, containing genealogical research for his book The Rhodes Family in America published in 1959, and containing information on the allied families of Ashby, Botts, Gaines, Graves, Lee, Madison, Pendleton, Taylor, Waterhouse, and Waters that settled in Culpeper, Loudoun, Orange, and Stafford Counties, Virginia, and Illinois, Kentucky, Massachusetts, North Carolina, and Ohio. The collection includes correspondence with family members and other researchers, and copies and transcriptions of census records, deed books, land grants and patents, military records, order books, tax lists, vital statistics, wills, and published sources. There are also copies of 19th century family letters, and genealogical charts and pedigrees.
Contents List
- Allied Families - Supporting Data. (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
- Ashby. (Box 1, Folder 4-6)
- Ashby - Oversize. (Box 20, Folder n/a)
- Baer, Mabel Van Dyke. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Record of the Bartholomew Family by George Wells Bartholomew, Jr.. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Beatty. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Beigel, Shirley B. - Correspondence. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Boss, Lula Reed - Correspondence. (Box 1, Folder 11-13)
- Boss, Lula Reed - Correspondence. (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
- Botts. (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
- Botts - Book One. (Box 2, Folder 5-11)
- Botts - Book Two. (Box 3, Folder 1-5)
- Botts - Book Three. (Box 3, Folder 6-12)
- Botts, Benjamin Gaines (1776-1811). (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Botts - Current. (Box 4, Folder 2-5)
- Botts, John (1754-1796) m. Lucy Gaines. (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
- Botts/Johnson. (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Botts, Rev. Joseph (1790-1880). (Box 4, Folder 9-12)
- Botts - Miscellaneous. (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
- Botts - Oversize. (Box 20, Folder n/a)
- Botts - Supporting Documents - Book Two. (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Botts, Thomas Hutchinson. (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Botts - Unplaced. (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Botts, Virginia M. - Correspondence. (Box 5, Folder 6-8)
- Bridwell. (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Charts. (Box 20, Folder n/a)
- Clovercroft Chronicles, 1814-1893 by Mary Rhoads Haines. (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Colonial Granville County and its People by Worth S. Ray. (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Colton Hall Museum (Monterey, CA) - Charles T. Botts. (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Correspondence (F-S). (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Correspondence (F-S). (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
- Davis, W. Pressley - Correspondence. (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Davis, W. Pressley - Taylor Records. (Box 6, Folder 5-6)
- Dawson. (Box 6, Folder 7)
- DeWolf. (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Dictionary of American Biography. (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Douglas. (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Gaines Family - Documentation. (Box 6, Folder 11-15)
- Gaines Family - Documentation. (Box 7, Folder 1-4)
- Gaines Family - Mildred Olevia Eubank Correspondence. (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Gaines Family - Marietta Gaines Memorandum Book. (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Gaines Family - Dr. John A. Kelly Correspondence. (Box 7, Folder 7-8)
- Gaines Family - Lucille Arnold Lawrence Lineage Chart. (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Gaines Family - Part I. (Box 7, Folder 10-12)
- Gaines Family - Part II. (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
- Gaines Family - Gaines, Robert Jr. (1772-1836). (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Gaines Family - Several Correspondents. (Box 8, Folder 4-5)
- Graves. (Box 8, Folder 6-7)
- Hening's Statutes - Index. (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Hoffman, Alice Taylor - Correspondence, August 1972 - June 1974. (Box 8, Folder 9-12)
- Hoffman, Alice Taylor - Correspondence, June-December 1974. (Box 9, Folder 1-4)
- Hoffman, Alice Taylor - Correspondence, 1975-1977. (Box 9, Folder 5-9)
- Hopkins-Lewis. (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Hull. (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Ingersoll. (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Irwin, Laura and Key, Lydia Botts - Correspondence. (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Jacklin. (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Jillson, Myrtle M.. (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Josserand, Gertrude - Correspondence,. (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Keener. (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Land Records. (Box 20, Folder n/a)
- Madison. (Box 10, Folder 2-3)
- James Madison by Irving Brant (Taylor Diary Documentation). (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Madison-Taylor-Gaines. (Box 10, Folder 5-7)
- Maulsby Family in America by Ella K. Barnard (Rhoades Family). (Box 10, Folder 8)
- McRoberts, Mary - Correspondence. (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Miscellaneous. (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Moses, Graham Lee. (Box 10, Folder 11-13)
- My Ancestry by Thomas L. Rhoads (Title Page). (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Nalle, William (Culpeper, VA). (Box 11, Folder 1)
- New England Historic Genealogical Society. (Box 11, Folder 2-3)
- North Carolina State Archives. (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Orcutt. (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Patton/Patten. (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Pendleton. (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Plat of Fowler Township, Trumbull County, 1938. (Box 20, Folder n/a)
- Prince. (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Donald Robertson and his Wife Rachel Rogers by Commodore Richard Taylor. (Box 11, Folder 9-10)
- Rhodes. (Box 11, Folder 11-12)
- The Rhodes Family in America - Orders. (Box 11, Folder 13-15)
- Rhodes, Hezekiah of Vermont. (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Rhodes, John (1747-1819. (Box 12, Folder 2-4)
- Rhodes, Joseph. (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Rhodes - Ohio. (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Rhodes-Pierson-Whipkey (Trumbull County, OH). (Box 12, Folder 7-8)
- "History of the Rogers Family" by Mary Frances (Rogers) Williamson. (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Rutty-Hull-Loomis. (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Sarver. (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Sheldon. (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Some Notable Families of America by Annah Robinson Watson. (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Sons of the Revolution/Sons of the American Revolution. (Box 12, Folder 14)
- The St. John Genealogy by Orline St. John Alexander. (Box 12, Folder 15)
- Stoltz, Eileen O. - Correspondence. (Box 12, Folder 16)
- Sutherd, Calvin E. - A Compilation of Gaines Family Data (photocopy). (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
- Sutherd, Calvin E. - A Compilation of Gaines Family Data - Indexed Edition and Supplement (2 vols.). (Box 19, Folder n/a)
- Sweetland (Emilie Kryder Correspondence). (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Taylor. (Box 13, Folder 4-5)
- Taylor Book - Appendix. (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Taylor Family - Charts and Miscellaneous. (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Taylor Family - Documentation (1 to 33). (Box 13, Folder 8-12)
- Taylor Family - Documentation (34 to 65). (Box 14, Folder 1-4)
- Taylor Family - Documentation (66 to 107). (Box 14, Folder 5-10)
- Taylor Family - Documentation (108 to 212). (Box 15, Folder 1-6)
- Taylor Family - Documentation (220 to 318). (Box 15, Folder 7-9)
- Taylor, Col. Francis - Diary Excerpts and Notes. (Box 15, Folder 10-12)
- Taylor, Col. Francis - Diary Transcription. (Box 16, Folder 1-4)
- Taylor, George E. - Correspondence. (Box 16, Folder 5-6)
- James Taylor of Virginia - Book 1, Part 1. (Box 16, Folder 7-9)
- James Taylor of Virginia - Book 1, Part 2. (Box 16, Folder 10-11)
- James Taylor of Virginia - Book 1, Part 2. (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
- James Taylor of Virginia - Book 1, Part 3. (Box 17, Folder 3-6)
- Taylor Family - Mary McRoberts Correspondence. (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Taylor Family - Miscellaneous. (Box 17, Folder 8)
- Taylor Family - Taylor, Noah. (Box 17, Folder 9)
- Taylor Family Notes by Anne Spotswood Dandridge. (Box 17, Folder 10-11)
- Taylor and Related Families. (Box 17, Folder 12)
- Taylor Family - Jessie Taylor Webb Correspondence. (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Templeman, Eleanor Lee - Correspondence. (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Thomas Family - Marybelle Weis Correspondence. (Box 18, Folder 3-4)
- "Three Centuries in America" - Allied Families. (Box 18, Folder 5-6)
- "Three Centuries in America" - Allied Families (P-Z) - Supporting Documents. (Box 18, Folder 7)
- Townsend, Mrs. Charles Delmar. (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Virginia Genealogical Society. (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Virginia State Library. (Box 18, Folder 10-12)
- Waterhouse-Stevens. (Box 19, Folder 1)
- Waterhouse-Waters. (Box 19, Folder 2-4)
- Waters. (Box 19, Folder 5-6)
- Wilkes. (Box 19, Folder 7)
- Winnagle, Grace M.. (Box 19, Folder 8)